[Music]
imagine two positive real numbers X and
Y represented by lengths of connected
line segments and then draw the
semicircle with diameter given by the
connected segments so that the radius of
the semicircle is x + y/ 2 then let Z be
the length of the half cord from the
point where X and Y meet to the
semicircle connecting the ends of the
diameter to the intersection of Z on the
circle yields a triangle and by the's
triangle theorem this triangle must be
right
angled consequently these two subt
triangles are similar so that the ratios
z overx and y over Z are equal we
conclude z^2 equals x * y so that Z is
the square root of x * y
no matter the lengths of X and Y the
chord length Z is always less than or
equal to the radius of the semicircle by
construction therefore the < TK of x * Y
is less than or equal to x + y / 2 with
equality if and only if xal y this is
the arithmetic mean geometric mean
inequality
[Music]